<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">

    <channel>
        <title>Eric Chrobak</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description>Eric Chrobak | Software Engineer
</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 22:47:18 -0500</lastBuildDate>
        
        <item>
            <title>Setup Your Ruby Environment</title>
            <link>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/08/15/Setting-Up-Your-Ruby-Environment.html
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Setting up your Ruby environment the first time is tricky. You end up banging your head against the and running down the street screaming if don’t do it correctly. I’m hoping to help other developers get their Ruby environment setup correctly the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll go over:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quo...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
            <guid>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/08/15/Setting-Up-Your-Ruby-Environment.html
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Deploying an AWS Lambda Ruby Function</title>
            <link>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/07/25/Deploying-Ruby-To-AWS-Lambda.html
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I needed a CD/CI pipeline to push Ruby apps to version control and deploy to AWS Lambda. The documentation out there is disjointed. I dealt with many issues and lots of trial and error trying to setup this process. It was crucial to have this pipeline setup so I can work on the applications no matter where I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do development in a variety of places i...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
            <guid>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/07/25/Deploying-Ruby-To-AWS-Lambda.html
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Extracting Data from JSON with Ruby</title>
            <link>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/09/13/Extract-Data-from-JSON-with-Ruby.html
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I have a simple app I built to receive a string and pass that string to a .txt file. The next goal of the application was to receive data from a .json file. The main hurdles that I had to face were setting headers and formatting the data to output to a file. That required a complete overhaul of the app. The initial application was a class with an initialize function, set h...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 22:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
            <guid>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/09/13/Extract-Data-from-JSON-with-Ruby.html
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How to Extend Your App</title>
            <link>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/08/29/How-To-Extend-Your-App.html
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I worked in construction previously and we built several home additions. These additions had to integrate with the existing systems of the home like the HVAC, plumbing, and electricity. If you are building up on the house then you have to consider load bearing walls, ventilation, roofing, adding staircases, etc. People are aware of this and don’t just start tearing off the...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
            <guid>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/08/29/How-To-Extend-Your-App.html
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Moving From Ruby To PHP</title>
            <link>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/08/23/Moving-From-Ruby-To-PHP.html
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
At my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vaspian.com&quot;&gt;9-5&lt;/a&gt; we provide a variety of telecom services to our clients and use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zoho.com/one/&quot;&gt;Zoho One&lt;/a&gt; as our ERP. We have a texting platform that sends out mass text messages on behalf of our clients. However, they need the phone numbers verified before sending the sms bl...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
            <guid>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/08/23/Moving-From-Ruby-To-PHP.html
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>I Repurposed a JavaScript chat app as an AI bot</title>
            <link>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/03/10/I-Repurposed-App-For-AI.html
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Recently, I had the opportunity to share about software development at a local high school career fair. I thought of what I might showcase to the students and thought back to an app I built in a JavaScript class. It received some input and output reponses to the input. My thought was to repurpose the app to receive students reason to learn programming, what they hope to le...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 21:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <guid>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/03/10/I-Repurposed-App-For-AI.html
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>What Can You Do With Ruby?</title>
            <link>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/01/31/What-Can-You-Do-With-Ruby.html
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Have you ever asked yourself questions like:
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What can I do with a programming language?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What can I do with plain/vanilla Ruby?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can I build an application without Rails?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do I need a frame...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 21:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <guid>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/01/31/What-Can-You-Do-With-Ruby.html
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>I Built A Basic Rails App</title>
            <link>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/12/16/Building-A-Basic-Rails-App.html
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve been developing for quite some time and had put my Ruby learning to the side but, it felt like to due time to get back in the saddle. So I started with the official &lt;a href=&quot;https://guides.rubyonrails.org/getting_started.html&quot;&gt;Ruby on Rails getting started with Rails Guide&lt;/a&gt;. I am going to talk about the steps necessary to build that first app,...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 21:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
            <guid>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/12/16/Building-A-Basic-Rails-App.html
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Deploying to Jekyll</title>
            <link>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/03/19/Deploying-To-Jekyll.html
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This site was started in 2016 as part of a Codecademy project. At the time it was built on HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, and JQuery. It went through a series of changes from there. With the main one being a css theme being added for the nav menu.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Over time I saw the maintenance of the site was becoming to much. Some of the things that were a bi...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
            <guid>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/03/19/Deploying-To-Jekyll.html
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Sinatra and MVC</title>
            <link>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/09/27/Sinatra-and-MVC.html
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Developing an app involves a level of complexity that would make using a single file for all the code completely useless. This is due the difficulty of debugging a large file and make changes when necessary. In addition such a file would be difficult to read.
&lt;br /&gt;
This is were frameworks come in such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://sinatrarb.com/&quot;&gt;Sinatra&lt;/a...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 12:54:10 -0500</pubDate>
            <guid>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/09/27/Sinatra-and-MVC.html
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>COFFEE, Coffee, and coffee...</title>
            <link>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/08/07/coffee-coffee-and-coffee.html
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Coffee and coding seem to go together like peanut butter and jelly. When I hunker down to work on a project there is nothing like a nice cup of java to get me going!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the course work at Flatiron a recent project required me to pull data from websites through a method called scraping. It works just like it sounds, you are literally scraping data off of a website. ...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:57:26 -0500</pubDate>
            <guid>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/08/07/coffee-coffee-and-coffee.html
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>LEARN IDE & General Keyboard Shorcuts</title>
            <link>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/08/03/learn-ide-and-general-keyboard-shorcuts.html
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;I love that coding and programming involves shortcuts to increase productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite shortcuts while working on a computer is keyboard shortcuts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will provide some common ones and then those more specific to Learn IDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CMD/⌘ - this is the Command/ button on the mac. PC users use your Ctrl(Control) key.
These ar...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 19:58:16 -0500</pubDate>
            <guid>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/08/03/learn-ide-and-general-keyboard-shorcuts.html
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Too Many Relationships!? Avoid Infinite Loops When Relating Objects</title>
            <link>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/06/19/too-many-relationships-avoid-infinite-loops-when-relating-objects.html
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Do you have too many relationships? Does your app have to many relationships? Actually what I’m wondering is do you get stuck in a loop with bad relationship(s)? Well I’m sure we’ve all been there where you just cant seem to break out of a bad loop when relating classes to one another(not unlike dating relationships!)I like how coding relates to real life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently ...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 14:38:42 -0500</pubDate>
            <guid>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/06/19/too-many-relationships-avoid-infinite-loops-when-relating-objects.html
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>OO TIC TAC TOE and Word to the wise&#58 Follow the Directions!</title>
            <link>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/08/oo-tic-tac-toe-and-word-to-the-wise-follow-the-directions.html
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Solving problems with programming is an open ended adventure. There are multiple ways to solve a problem, present an idea, or make something. My most frustrating experience thus far in coding was a project I had for an online coding program I’m doing with Flatiron School. My goal was to build an Object Oriented TIC TAC TOE game in the command line. I had already built one but there was...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 17:55:19 -0500</pubDate>
            <guid>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/08/oo-tic-tac-toe-and-word-to-the-wise-follow-the-directions.html
            </guid>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A Reason to Code</title>
            <link>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/11/a-reason-to-code.html
            </link>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Computer programming/coding started out as the domain of “geeks”, “nerds”, and “hackers” from the 50’s up until the last 10-15 years. Around the time of the dotcom burst of the the late 90’s many more people started pursuing careers in programming(coding). What was once a job behind a honking monitor with slacks, tie, and pens in the front pocket has become a hip job associated with pe...
            </description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 19:35:43 -0500</pubDate>
            <guid>
                http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/04/11/a-reason-to-code.html
            </guid>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
